

PRODUCT & DIGITAL DESIGNER

CONTACT

daniel.rajendran@gmail.com



PORTFOLIO

danonthe.net

behance.net/danielrajendran

SOCIALS

- instagram.com/danrajendran
- twitter.com/danrajendran
- linkedin.com/in/danielrajendran

SKILLS

Process: Wireframing, Rapid prototyping, Agile development, Responsive design, High-fidelity design, Web design, User journeys, Storytelling, Interaction design

Applications: Sketch, Figma, Adobe XD, Miro, Marvel, InVision, Balsamiq, Zeplin, InDesign, Photoshop, Illustrator

Technology: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, jQuery UI, PHP

Delivery: Cross-browser compliance, Fluid grids, Cross-client compliance, SEO, Print-ready markup

Systems: Pendo, Product Board, Google Analytics, HotJar, WordPress, Jekyll, Marketo, SalesForce, MailChimp, Aprimo, Eloqua, SharePoint

Other: Photo editing, Photography, Copy writing, Illustration, Iconography

ABOUT

I'm a multi-format designer with over 11 years of experience working in fast-paced tech companies. I've experienced the rush of rapid startup growth, the pressure of a big partnership with Facebook, and the ever-shifting priorities of work at a consultancy. In my different roles I've gained experience working across many design mediums, and over time I've found my passion is to design and build beautiful things, from icons and apps to posters and products.

I'm happiest as part of a team where I can learn from others and improve my own skills. I've learned from experience that research and data gathering are inherent to making good decisions, and that collaborative iteration is a key part of my role. I've got a proven ability to deliver on time, relish learning new skills, and always strive to embrace challenges outside of my comfort zone.

EXPERIENCE



Senior Product Designer for Concirrus INSURANCE INSIGHT March 2019 - present



- Joined as sole product designer for Quest Automotive, a web platform designed to provide risk management insight and visualisation for insurance companies
- Saw features from discovery through to release, including problem definition, user research, sketching, prototyping, user testing, high-fedilty design creation, and feedback gathering
- Completely restructured and componentised the Quest Automotive design files in Sketch
- Was a key part of launching Quest Automotive to our first customer and gathering feedback
- Migrated Quest Automotive designs to Figma and established a cross-product master library to develop a shared design language between our three core product teams
- Designed and prototyped a mobile app for our first internal hackathon, to deliver key features of the Quest Automotive web app to fleet managers operating in the field
- Lead discovery and design of a new 'Submissions' feature for Quest Marine, to allow marine insurance underwriters to more easily assess the potential risk of inbound business
- Assisted in the creation, design, and launch of completely revamped company values



Product Designer for Content and Code SHAREPOINT OFFICE 365 INTRANET June 2017 — February 2019

- A key part of driving Fresh, the company's Intranet-In-A-Box, through several major product milestones, designing key new features that improved usability and increased sales
- Designed the Fresh Mobile app for iOS/Android from the ground up
- Supported a major platform transition to rebuild Fresh using Modern SharePoint
- Lead a project to update the Fresh visual brand, adapting the original pop-art styling to be usable in more situations and formats, without sacrificing the unique visual identity
- Designed all new features and layouts for Fresh, updating existing UI components to suit
- Completely redesigned the Content and Code and Fresh commercial websites to improve user flow and site load times, and reduce overhead caused by over-reliance on WordPress plugins



Front-End Designer/Developer for DataSift BIG DATA SOCIAL MEDIA INSIGHT

January 2015 — December 2016

- Played an instrumental part in launching our Facebook Topic Data platform, creating new web content and print collateral, as well as co-ordinating launch of said content
- Lead a project to move legacy sites from Drupal to WordPress for easier management
- Ran 'Lunch and Learn' sessions about how design and branding serves the business
- Designed new lead tracking and scoring systems to more greatly improve website lead quality
- Responsible for design, coding, QA, and maintenance for all commercial websites
- Assisted the product team with visual design and UX prototyping for a new product offering
- Designed numerous ebooks, one pagers, banners, and other sales and marketing collateral



PRODUCT & DIGITAL DESIGNER

CONTACT

daniel.rajendran@gmail.com

07708698413

PORTFOLIO

danonthe.net

Be behance.net/danielrajendran

SOCIALS

- instagram.com/danrajendran
- twitter.com/danrajendran
- in linkedin.com/in/danielrajendran

REFERENCES

Available upon request

EXPERIENCE (CONTINUED)



Web Designer for Huddle CLOUD COLLABORATION FILE SHARING CO
January 2010 — December 2014

- Acted as the only design and development resource for the commercial arm of the company
- Joined as Design Intern, and was promoted to Junior Designer, Designer, then Web Designer
- Lead a team that redesigned the home page and free trial process to increase lead gen 180%
- Handled end to end process for the marketing site, blog, and help desk, including page design, coding, QA, deployment and maintenance, as well as copywriting and illustration
- Assisted in a complete company rebrand, and then lead a full redesign of the marketing site
- Help establish hackathons, various social clubs, and other key aspects of the company culture

EDUCATION



BSc Computing and Interaction Design at Goldsmiths College, University of London September 2006 — August 2009

- Focused on web design and technologies, user experience, and interaction design
- Covered computer science topics such as object oriented programming and database design
- Final project was a human interaction device that could manipulate 3D models in real-time.



BEng Computer and Network Engineering at **University of Westminster** September 2004 — Jan 2006

- Computer science style degree that focused on network engineering and programming
- Also included foundational topics such as electrical engineering and applied mathematics
- Transferred during my 2nd year to pursue a more design oriented degree

INTERESTS

I've always been a creator at heart, whether it was clicking Lego bricks together as a child, building my own computers as a teenager, or weaving my own stories in Dungeons & Dragons as an adult. I'm always on the lookout for inspiration for my own projects, so I've always got a book or two on the go and a long list of podcasts to listen to when I'm out and about. I enjoy DIY and I've recently acquired a couple of 3D printers and have started dabbling with resin casting to expand what projects I can tackle.

I love living in a city like London and usually spend at least part of my weekend out of the house, exploring areas I've not yet seen or visiting some old favourites, especially the greener parts. I'm also a frequent visitor of ZSL London Zoo, the Natural History Museum, the Design Museum, and the Royal Albert Hall, all of which I have become a member of in the last few years.

When I'm not doing any of the above, I love spending time playing games of all sorts, whether they be computer games, card games, board games, escape rooms, or tabletop RPGs.